all right I know all the concepts I know
everything but all I need to know right
now is how to actually get into a trade
with a systematic entry strategy if you
have this question in this video I'm
gonna have you covered because in
today's lesson we're gonna address how
to actually enter trades both as a swing
and day trader while covering time
frames top-down analysis and two
systematic ways of entering the market
this is also the last video of the
technical analysis video series so you
better cut all distractions right now
put down your phone close your charts
right get at a quiet place and make this
time investment to carefully study the
content take notes and apply on your
charts and make sure that you're well up
to date with the previous content we had
in the previous videos because if you're
not you're gonna get lost right because
this series is designed to take you by
the hand step by step build all the
tools you need in order to be a
profitable Trader also make sure to
visit the link in the description as I
have some more gifts for you down there
and without further Ado I I think it's
time to get into the video because again
entries is what everybody wants to learn
all right let's learn how to enter into
trades so what are the few important
aspects of entries you think it's all
about getting that sniper entry getting
that high Precision one pip stop loss
like going to extreme Precision not
really it's all about actually being
systematic and finding a way for you to
enter the same traits over and over and
over again without doubting too much and
without being like okay should I enter
here should I enter there no right but
in order to get there you have to go
through a couple of important parts of
entries the first one is time frames you
have to give each time frame a task
because without proper top-down analysis
you cannot get into high probability
entry right you can't just go to the one
minute and get a sniper range without
having any context at all and this is
why where a lot of people go wrong is
that they go instead of first learning
how to analyze Market structure trending
markets supply and demand minor major
structure right they jump onto entries
because they think if you get the entry
criteria good you're gonna win no the
entries pretty much twenty percent of
the of it all right so again what you
have to do is you have to determine what
is the aim of each time frame so what
are you going to be looking for on this
time frame what you're going to be
looking on the second time frame what
you're going to be looking on the third
time right so each time frame has a task
and we're gonna address this in this
video then you have to Define your entry
criteria to the fullest so usually
before you take a trade you need to see
a series of events before you engage in
a trade so how does that series of event
look like what do you want to see okay
then of course you have to determine
what is your required stop loss and take
profit when it comes to your risk to
reward okay so like uh for example for
myself if I take my uh conservative
entries which I'm about to teach you I
require a stop loss of five Pips why
because I want to be out of the trade
when 20 when it moves 25 Pips in profit
okay I don't want to be swinging it for
60 Pips relying on the market to give me
60 Pips of movement while I can be out
in just 25 and call it a day okay so you
need a checklist of steps that you need
to take before you take every trade and
also I'm gonna offering you a cheat
sheet for that at the end okay
next thing refining your trade
management to the fullest as well
because after you enter a trade amazing
but what then when do you go break even
are you gonna take partials are you
gonna move your stop-loss in profit are
you gonna Trail your trade right what
are you gonna do after the trade and
this is also where a lot of people also
go wrong is that you enter a trade and
then you just pretty much screw it over
you either go break even get stopless
then hit stake profit or you are take
like a big portion and it continues to
go into profit or you can do a lot of
things that can screw your overall
performance so again the third part is
what are you gonna do when your trade is
running into profit okay and pretty much
that's it it's simple the next thing you
have to do is learning how to let go of
the outcome of the trade and just pretty
much thinking probabilities and think
long term because if you have the best
entry strategy but you have a float
mindset you do not allow the trade to
play out to the fullest you you go break
even too fast you're fearful to take the
trade according to your rules uh you
close the trade when it's half of your
stop loss when you shouldn't close right
you will still fail
okay so also it's all a mindset game so
let's address all of these aspects
aspects one by one let's touch on
trading time frames so how to understand
time frames and which ones to trade on
so first of all what do time frames mean
okay we've covered this in the previous
lesson but as I told you price is always
the same and time frames are just a
different representation of price
right even if you're on the one yearly
time frame or if you go all the way to
the one minute time frame price is price
it has done the same but just you get
very little data on the on the one
yearly but on the one minute you get
lots of data you get candles every
single minute okay so price is always
the same what is different is the amount
of information and depth of detail you
see and again many Traders fixate their
minds on different time frames thinking
they're all different right so like the
one hourly it's different than the
flowery or the 15 minute is better than
the five minute no they are all the same
it's just the difference of the depth of
detail and again you have to be
systematic
as I told you the market is fractal so
you can reach the forward time frame how
it look how the forwarded time frame
looks like even if you're on your 15
minute chart I can very easily do that
or you can be on the one minute chart
but read how the 50 minute is looking
like okay this is a great exercise you
can do like go to your one minute time
frame and try to draw how the 15 minute
time frame is gonna look like this takes
experience but there Comes A Time In
which you can be just looking at one
time frame but also reading the hard
time frames although I don't do this and
I don't advise doing it because again
you need to look at the precise details
on each time frame you're using
again going back to previous lessons the
higher time frames is where the money is
this is where the bfis potentially
operate and this is where we follow
their footsteps because if you stay on
the one minute on the smallest time
frame you're always going to have big
pushes you're always going to have big
impulses and big initiations but again
they don't hold much value well if you
have a massive daily initiation a
massive daily push well
somebody's driving the price on the
daily to the upside well it means that
we're in an uptrend okay so hard
timeframes will always prevail
so again we simply want to follow the
trend of the high time frame and again
the quarterly is going to Prevail over
the week the weekly is going to Prevail
over the daily day lower 4-H Voyage over
50 minutes and 50 minutes over one
minute so if you are bearish on the
footage and all of a sudden it starts
massively going up then of course you go
to the Daily and you see ah daily is
bullish if you are bullish on The Daily
but it goes down you go to the weekly ah
weekly is bearish right because usually
hard time frames will prevail and if
you're on the hard time frames there is
less noise which makes it easy to
identify the main Direction so again
always have a hard time frame in your
mix
lower time frames are only for entries
and refinements okay you don't stay on
the lower time frames the majority of
your time is spent on the hard time
frames like 4-H or 50 minute we're gonna
go into that okay but only once you know
what price is doing on the hard time
frame then you drop to the lower time
frame and search for your entry criteria
that's it again I know a lot of
strategies they just stay for example on
the five minute and scalp on the five
minute
that's fine if it works for you great
but if you really want to build a true
Edge you need hard time frames and you
do not drop to the lower time frames
without having your hard time frame
structure zones ranges the 50 range
right your supply and demand zones and
everything that I taught you so far so
let's explore time frames and pretty
much I'm gonna share with you which time
frames I use and or just give you like a
little bit of an overview what you you
could be using because again here I'm
not teaching you like a very specific
strategy I do this in my private program
because this is pretty much how I trade
but again I give you all the tools so
you can actually go out there and build
your strategy first of all major big
hard time frame BFI Direction BFI is
Banks and financial institutions because
again in our Forex space this is what
they say hard time from this is where
the banks trade do they really trade
there probably not right but this is
what we're told again this is how we
think and again it usually makes sense
okay so those time frames are again the
big guys as we mentioned that is pretty
much your macro Trend and again always
be aware where prices in terms of the
macro Trend are there any important
zones where currently prices okay I
personally I say it a lot on my weekly
outlooks but I do not like major time
frames because they take way too much
time to to develop and me as a day
trader scalper I don't need to know what
is happening on the monthly time frame
so I can take my trains on the one
minute okay but if you are a swing
Trader major time frames absolutely
essential okay
to me the forward time frame is the
absolute golden time frame so to me this
is the main time frame for direction
this is my major structure this is where
I identify my Trend my ranges my PD
premium discounts my major structural
levels my weak and strong highs and lows
my supply and demand zones everything
okay so this is the best time part this
is the best higher time frame for day
Traders I am a day trader so this is my
hard time frame on a daily basis I do
not go to the Daily or to the wiggler to
the monthly all I check in the morning
is the flower time frame okay if you are
a swing Trader you can of course use the
daily as well okay again I'm giving you
all the time frame so you tweak
according to your approach and according
to your style of training then
we need a minor structure time frame and
this is where you actually jump on on a
lower time frame than your major time
frame right to actually look at how the
market is looking like within those legs
and this again guys we go back to Market
structure video this is major minor
structure for all the time frame that's
your major 50 minute time frame that's
your minor okay and you can be using
anything in between the 15 and the 60
Minutes the hourly time frame all right
but again you always link this towards
your major time frame so according to
the formally time frame and according to
the following major structure how does
the minor structure look like because
the amount of structure is going to be
in between the major one and this is
where we usually capitalize on
continuations And pullback Trades again
just to give you a very brief example
with my little pen
on the 40 time frame we have a push and
we're starting a pullback okay so that
is our Harlow that is our high that's
our major structure there's our 50 but
then of course if you take all of this
and you go to the 15 minute which is our
minor structure right we're going to
have like a massive uptrend the Mark is
going to reach the top it's going to
make a trend change so right now we're
starting to pull back so I know that my
50 is here I know that the market has
already shifting structure so what I'm
going to be doing is I'm going to be
working
with the minor structure in order to get
me towards the major one so I can take a
couple of shorts until we tap 50 then as
we top 50 knowing we're bullish I'm
gonna be looking for the market to align
and that is when I'm gonna start taking
Longs okay that is the aim of the minor
time frame to give you more details on
how your major time frame looks like and
how to position yourself in a more uh
how to say like a specific yet refined
entry okay because you don't just want
to plot a Buy on the photo right there
and place your stop loss below you want
to be a little bit more precise and we
get this Precision by having a minor
time frame okay and again this is Market
structure video go back watch it Angel
time frames is where you go to if even
if you really want to refine that's when
you go to the angel time frames so after
you determine your minor time frame
positioning okay you have your entry
Zone and then price Taps into your entry
Zone that is when you drop lower if you
wish to find an entry and on that entry
time frame you have to be as detailed as
possible regarding your rules because
you can be all over the place right so
again same example push and pull back on
the Folly time frame we are bullish the
50 minute is currently in a downtrend
and just recently after tapping the 50
it made a bullish Trend change there is
our Zone okay so again we Define our
entry Zone the price Taps into the entry
Zone and it is that moment where we
actually go to the one minute and again
you just take this little piece of
information and it looks like a little
uptrend then it goes like a downtrend so
you just wait for the market to align
and then you go up it's fractal
everything repeats on the same time
frame and of course we're going to jump
into examples we're all Theory right now
so with that's being said what does this
do this builds your top-down analysis
process so let me give you uh an example
process weekly or daily where are we
there is it pushing or pulling back is
it in premium or discount right now what
makes sense to trade War where are the
banks going are there any important
levels to be aware of this is the only
thing I do on the weekend daily I don't
draw structure there I don't draw PD
ranges I don't draw anything I only need
to know okay what is that time frame
doing so it may it gives me a little bit
of an edge
okay then follow the time frame is where
I spend the well not the majority but
this is where I get my hard time from
Direction so there what is the trend and
what is the market structure okay so
what is the trend is an uptrend is the
downtrend is it a consolidation is it
currently in a push phase towards the
week
a lower high or is in the pullback phase
towards premium discount what I mean by
that do we have a push we have a
pullback so is the market currently in a
push phase towards the weak High which
is right there so we're already having
like a push or did the market push and
it's currently correcting towards 50 so
those are usually the two phases you're
gonna have your other gonna be in a push
phase towards the high or you're either
going to be in a pullback phase right
towards making a potential hard low
formation this is the main thing you
need on the forward time frame and of
course your major Harlow and your major
High because this pretty much determines
your major range
okay
then 15 minutes injury price and zones
this is again where I spend the majority
of my time every day I pretty much stay
on the 15 minute because I know how the
forward time frame looks like so all I
do is stay on the 50 minutes and this is
why I draw my introduce intraday price
intraday zones and again this is where I
try to align with the forwarded time
frame for continuations or of course
look for the uh for the retracement
trades so for retracement trades once
again you have to wait for a TC so if
you have an uptrend the market starts
pulling back you need that TC on the top
of the floor High okay or if you want to
get into continuation you again need for
the 50 minute to be aligned with the
quality time frame so then you can start
looking for the continuation okay
and of course there are numerous details
that we're going to be addressing right
now I'm going to be giving you plenty of
examples if you want to go into a
continuation okay you usually have to
wait for the quality time frame to top
50 of the leg okay or if you're trading
into a retracement you trade it only
until the 50 because when it Taps 50 you
usually know that the market pushes has
pulled back 50 steps you can go for a
new high so if you still look for shorts
right there it doesn't make a lot of
sense okay and on the 50 minute it's
always very important that you draw your
zones and your structure breaks and your
Trend changes it's exactly the same
thing you do in the footage you do it on
the 50 minute which is internal of the
voyage
and then you have your ancient time
frame so this is from the one to five
minutes you have first of all you have
your intraday Zone which is on the 15
minute as the zone is tapped that is
when you drop to the one to the five
minute time frame and you look for your
entry rules
all right so you're probably tired of
theory let's get it to the end revisit
all of this because it's a lot of notes
I want you to pause the video study what
I have said right there it's a lesson
it's a lecture you have to pause you
have to take notes okay because that's a
lot of things but I always want to go
through the examples because there it
really makes sense so
how to trade from those supply and
demand zones okay so you have your
quality Trend you have your uh 15 minute
Alliance you have your 50 minute Zone
what do you do
as I keep saying this is a concept that
I really want to ingrain into your head
the market has a fractal nature so any
setup you see on the monthly time frame
will repeat on the one minute and the
other way around
okay it's just a matter of preference
which time frame you're going to be
using
in this video I'm going to give you two
types of simple entries okay so very
simple
first is an aggressive entry from The
Zone okay so you're going to need a
little bit of a bigger stop loss
although there are ways to get the stop
loss Tighter and the second one is the
conservative entry which is after making
a which is pretty much waiting for a
structure shift inside the supply and
demand Zone which utilizes the lower
time frames so here's how the aggressive
entry looks like you have a Zone you
take the trade stop loss below the zone
and then you target the new high or you
wait you wait for exactly the same trade
but as we tap the zone right as we tap
the zone right there this is where you
go to a lower time frame and you simply
wait for an inch opportunity
right there
so with that being said let's actually
jump into the entry strategies the first
strategy I want to teach you is the set
and forget entry this is perfect for
swing Traders there are two things to
remember you always need to know what is
your hard time frame doing
what is your full hourly timeframe doing
okay so what is the major Market
Direction because this is usually going
to offer you the highest probability
trade and also what is your middle time
frame doing which illustrates your minor
structure and your ranges within the
major structure okay so in order to get
a high probability trade you need to
wait for the middle time frame to either
align with the major or to be like in a
pullback phase
so more examples coming in where the
staff entries set and forget it's always
preferred to stick to the hard time from
Trend so to trade Pro Trend and not go
against it
okay so it's always good to take those
entry entries at extreme points on a
hard time frame sorry art are going to
be like at the higher high or a lower
low or higher low or lower high what I
mean by this right so extreme point
is when the market pushes it pulls back
and it makes the exactly the first Trend
change that is an extreme Point why
because it's the hard high the market
pushes it pulls back
towards discount
there is Discount there is premium it
makes the trend change that is an
extreme point because it's a potential
flight high low okay if you find
yourself taking trades like this in the
middle you're probably gonna get swept
quite a few times okay because the
market when it's in the middle right
there it's not at an extreme point of a
Harlow or at the high it tends to kind
of change a couple of times before it
actually moves so again it's always good
to trade at extreme points okay for this
uh entry is also very important to not
micromanage your stop loss you place
your stop loss it's usually below or
above the zone you let it go okay and
always Draw Bigger zones don't refine
too much results in order to get a tight
stop loss just keep it big
for me I use my forward time frame
that's my hard time frame and then 50
minute as my middle time frame very very
simple let's look at some examples
so there's the data so again I try to to
be a little bit more
um kind of outside of what I do because
I want to offer you multiple
opportunities to to figure out your
trading strategy this is the daily
okay the daily it broke structure down
here it broke structure up there so we
have a trend change the market has
pulled back below 50 there is our major
low there is our major High the market
is below 50 so again if I ask you what
makes sense to be traded right now is it
shorts or is it Longs well hope will you
say Longs because we're bullish okay
going on to the next one so there is
that 50 on the daily so again so the
flow at the time frame right now acts as
our kind of minor time frame okay so
daily is bullish but again you can see
the forward time frame is going bearish
so what we have to wait for is for the
40 time frame to align there's a lower
low
we got a lower high the market failed to
break it right here it pulled back again
and that is where we broke it what
caused the break you track it back there
is the the the the point of the brake
okay then what happens is the market
goes on and aligns bullish on the forage
again guys Wix are breaks to me
hopefully you know this by now we have
probably break okay so now the daily
time frame
is bullish body time frame is bullish so
you have two conferences there is your
flowery Harlow there is your quality
higher high well this is not a higher
low because it's the low that I should
cause the brake so this is an extreme
point
okay so this is a higher low on The
Daily and right now it's the first low
as the fall of the time frame shift to
structure you draw your range you wait
for the market to be below 50 there it
is and at this Zone that is where you
decide again if you want to swing trade
it you can just simply take a trade from
here stop loss below or what I'm gonna
show you right now is you can drop to
even lower time frame
and utilize the saf entry which is on
the 50 minute so there's your
minor structure right now okay Wally
Harlow volley High the market is below
the 50 what it's doing is going in the
downtrend what you have to wait for is
right now for the 15 minute to also go
bullish and find a place from where it
actually went bullish okay so we have a
lower low right there we have a lower
high the market actually created an MSS
formation right there and broke the last
lower high okay so this is a valid lower
high right there it broke it up what
caused the break it's this Zone the
market pulls back take your entry stop
loss below right there and
there's a trade
again this one are Cherry Picked so
don't call me out yes I went on and I
picked those to be perfect because I can
show I want to show you a perfect
example later we're gonna go on the
charts and we're gonna see that it
doesn't work every single time okay but
for me it's important for you to see the
examples okay so again what you can do
in this case is again as I told you
there are ways to refine your your zones
you can take like 25 of the Zone 50 of
the zone you can take it from the top
this I leave up to you to test out what
works best and again your target is
usually going to be the week high and
that was on the voyage
or you can also Target a 50-minute week
high but again if you're trading from a
bullish daily a bullish forage right a
bullish 15 minute time frame you have a
very big chance that the market is going
to go up okay so that's first example in
which we used actually three time frames
okay major time frame on The Daily
bullish minor time frame on the flowery
bullish and then 50 minute time frame
into time frame we waited for it to
align and we took our trade
okay
next example again daily time frame so
this is really swing trading right there
daily time frame is bearish okay there
is our last break of structure
what caused the break it's this range
high range low the market just kissed 50
so what makes sense right now to be
traded is it long since it shorts in
terms of the daily
well hopefully you say shorts because
it's bearish buys let's see how the 40
time looks like oh well for the time
frame is too bullish it got all of this
shitty price action right there all of
this range okay but what is the current
what is the current range well the
market so again we're not gonna go into
Market structure details okay so you
should be doing this by now following
the structure okay from the previous
video this is the Harlow this is the
hard high where is the 50 right there
where is the Demand right here so
technically you can see the daily is
bearish right now
but the forward time frame is bullish
but where are we right now we are at a
higher high so what we could expect
happening is to for the market to pull
back and drive us into 50 so what are we
gonna do right here is we're gonna take
a counter Trend trade because right now
the 40 time frames 2 hasn't aligned can
you do that yes
if you are remember a very important
point from the theory before if you are
at extreme points if you are somewhere
right there in the middle you don't do
this you only do this at our highs or at
lower lows or right at harlows like here
in this case we have a higher high
jumping on the 15 minute there it is so
we have the Asian high uh kind of chop
for a little bit right there again the
15 minute was bullish from here breaking
structure up that was our demand the
market responded but then what it ended
up doing Trend change so right now we
know that this was our flowery Heart
High how do we know that a higher high
is formed when you have a 50 minute
train change a train changes right we
have our range Supply again you you pick
what to choose do you want to take this
do you want to take this do you want to
take this or do you want to take even
this it's up to you right I want you to
go and back this and figure out your
zones okay I just picked like this
overall range which is the last kind of
buy range initiation outside and this is
where I'm going to be setting my short
order
guess what the market didn't tap do we
care not really okay what the market
does it continues to go down but as you
can see right here
it's just up the 50 so you should know
that your probability of getting a short
trade right now decreases but let's not
forget that the daily Is bearish So
eventually the flower is going to go
from bullish to bearish and again this
is why I really love the the 50 minute
time frame because that's the first time
and that is actually going to show you
when this happens
so what we have we have again base
Supply going back to supply and demand
lessons we have a valid range right
there the 15 minute block structure
created the base Supply can we trade
from this absolutely yes
okay
Market comes back retests of course your
stop loss should always go above the
high right don't place it here you don't
place it anywhere apart from the height
and you do not micromanage what happens
later well let me delete my tools right
there the market goes on and makes
another structure break we track it back
what caused the break this is the high
so this is our Strong high right now our
trade is running into profit we have a
new Strong high can we keep shorting
absolutely we can short until we are
wrong there is our supply stop loss
above let's see what happens
the market pulls back
where's my mouse
was disappeared all right there it is so
the market pulls back Taps inside the
the lower high stop loss above and just
dumps so we hit 4r on the first trade we
hit 4r on the second trade okay we had a
new breaker structure what caused it
it's this can we set a new order here
absolutely but again the market does not
pull back and you break a structure what
caused the break it's this we set the
New Order the market doesn't come back
new breaker structure here this is what
caused it maybe you're getting right
there and you can see it just continues
to roll down
so we were bearish on the daily that was
our major time frame Direction okay but
on and for example on the 50 minute
right there we just kept getting short
and this is pretty much the set and
forget approach we're gonna go into the
live charts later and get some more
examples so hopefully it makes sense if
you have any questions the comments are
open below
the Precision entry
I know you're all here for this so let's
have a look
first again hard time frame Major Market
direction is it bullish is it bearish
middle time frame what is the minor
structure within the major structure
what is currently happening so again
let's not forget follow the time frame
is right there 50 minutes is right there
but this time we also have a lower entry
time frame that gives us energy criteria
and signals so again to me this is the
one minute time frame although
oftentimes I regret using the one minute
because it could be noisy it could give
you a couple of stop losses but you also
have to be fine with that
while do you need for precision entries
you need to have Mastery over your
higher emitter time frames because you
only go to lower time frames after Joe's
2 are ready
you need to have precise and strict
rules to let you know exactly what
you're looking for on the lower time
frames so don't just go out go there
without knowing what you're going to be
looking for you have to be patient and
wait for your strict rules to play out
because if you go fomo and you don't
wait for your rules to play out you're
gonna take losses okay and of course the
biggest drawdown of this one is you have
time you need time to stay on the charts
and monitor it on the lower time frame
because again when you drop to the one
minute it can take 30 minutes until your
setup comes on and you have to be there
because it only costs you one minute to
miss the trade and that's the biggest
drawdown of
training on a lower time frames okay the
good thing is that for precision entries
we utilize exactly the same steps as the
set and forget entry but again once we
have a tap of a supply and demand Zone
on the 50 minute that is where you drop
even lower and then we wait for a series
of events to occur what are those let's
have a look
here are the rules okay so first we have
our
we have our set and forget engine
criteria fulfilled so we have over 40
Trend check we have our 50 minute Zone
check we have our 50 minute PD range
check always good okay then as this zone
is tapped that is when we drop to the
lower time frame which for me is the one
minute time frame we wait for the for
our liquidity point to be taken so there
is a series of events
five things to happen before you take a
trade first Trend second
minor structure minor structure POI and
range good everything is met lower time
frame okay you drop as the Zone tops
lower time and what do you look for
there you wait for liquidity points to
be grabbed again liquidity lessons this
is pretty much you do this in order to
trick early bars and sellers get their
stop loss then usually your trade gets a
much bigger probability you can remove
this on on from your rules right but
again you might take one or two stop
losses before you get the winner so you
better wait for some sort of a liquidity
grab before you take the trade then what
you simply wait
Trend change and you know how train
change works because it works on
absolutely every single time frame so
what you're looking for here is for your
one minute the lower time frame to align
with the 50 minute very simple we did
this exactly this with the saf entry
right now we're going to be doing with
with this the only difference here
is that we also look for a liquidity
graph
okay and then what we have to find out
is okay what is the supply and demand
Zone that caused the one minute TC and
we enter from there and we place a safe
stop loss so if you want to visualize
this again quality time frame broke
structure major Harlow major higher high
fifty percent what do we look for is
wait for the market to pull back below
50 in order to get a higher probability
long trade okay then as soon as it's
here we'll drop to the 50 minute the 50
minute is going to be bearish because if
You observe this leg right there the 15
minute is going to be bearish what we
wait for is for the 50 minute to align
with the 4-H how do we know that it
aligns Trend change there's our train
change again price is fractal we have a
50 range right there we also have 50
range on the 50 minute you can
definitely do that the market pulls back
below 50 it Taps into the hard time from
the mat and again for your saf entry you
just enter from here stop loss below
easy but if you want to do the Precision
entry you drop to a lower time frame
okay and what you wait for it on the
lower time frame is again for that same
alignment but the only difference as I
keep saying is that you can wait for
liquidity graph so the market Taps into
your Zone creates a flat blows creates
equal lows creates maybe a fake TC
creates a little bit of a range
manipulates it okay so wait for this
don't rush to enter on the First Signal
because it's usually on a lower time
frame there is a lot of noise while on
the 15 minute diffusion Center from here
it can come in do all this BS and then
it's gonna go but your stop loss is safe
but if you go in on the one minute right
there Energy Center from here stop loss
below you're gonna get stopped
right so again what you wait for is
first liquidity grab train change
you find what caused the train change
you enter from there stop loss below
easy
right it's very very easy let's have a
look at some examples
there it is so here we're in the voyage
that's us-30 on the voyage okay so we
have a break of structure
um yeah probably we had one right there
so then we have a breaker structure here
bullish where is the low right there is
the high right there right so here we
can be looking to short on the 50mm but
right now we're focused on Pro Trend
we're focused on Longs okay we are below
the 50 so we're potentially about to
make a new high low formation for us to
head into the highs and take out the
flowerly weak High dropping on to the 50
minute okay the 50 minute was bearish
bearish bearish bearish right broke
structure down respected can you be
taking shorts here yes
as we saw in the previous example right
as long as the 15 minute goes down you
can be taking shorts I mean there is a
break of structure there is your Zone
take it set and forget or even drop to
the one minute to look for your short
but eventually what happens is the
market consolidates for a little bit
right there and then massively expands
okay then again what happens right now
is that the forwarded time frame was
bullish
and right now the 50 minute time frame
was bullish if you want to make this
clear I used to on here in my top right
corner I used to write these things down
okay flowery bullish 15 minute bearish
so what I had to wait for is for that 15
minute to align with the footage you can
definitely do that okay so we have right
now is a massive alignment so what we
have to wait for right now is for our
Zone to tap simple you don't trade
without having a Zone
you don't trade from the middle there it
is no Market comes back Taps into our
zone so again you can either do a set
and forget approach right here and just
enter from right there
no stop loss below but in this case
we're going to drop to lower time frame
and see what we can do right there there
it is so again you have to wait for some
sort of liquidity liquidity was even
forming right there you see this trend
line the market massively smashed it
right but again we look at structure we
don't look at trend lines we look at
structure the market broke here yes that
was the major Harlow formation but again
this is a higher high you don't want a
lunk right there train change Can you
short yes right but this is the one
minute you don't do this the market came
all the way down right here and as it
tapped The Zone it made a TC so again
there are multiple sorts of liquidity
okay we covered a lot of them in this
case what we have is not a liquidity
within here but liquidity happened right
there because again here you can see the
market shifts bearish all of this is
trend line liquidity all of this is also
liquidity the market comes in starts
making like a fake TC right there so you
can see tops it makes a fake internal TC
all right but again you ask the question
what is the the supply and demand Zone
that actually caused the first TC
there's our first DC there's the demands
are not caused it so you want to trade
from this one you don't want to do all
of that middle thing right there again
you trade from the extremes remember
going back to previous lesson you take
the trade from there
and you get 5r at a potential like
liquidity point or you can swing it to
the fences I don't know what happens
right let's see boom
there's your weak high so again you also
have to think of okay what is my trade
management how am I gonna approach this
okay but again this is a great example
of uh liquidity not being perfect but
again if you have your rules if you know
that the 50 minute is bullish wait for
the one minute to align you ask the
question what caused the one minute to
align and this is where you take your
trade okay and again guys saying it
again those are Cherry Picked yes I went
on the charts I uh backtest and I found
examples that look good so I can show
you good examples okay
another trade EU time EU time frame Euro
USD 40 time in bearish right so again
you can see where's my mouse uh keeps
disappearing there's brake construction
down okay what caused it this the market
pulls back shorts right there another
break of structure what caused it uh
it's this in this case you can see I
forgot to mark it right there we shifted
bullish for a little while so here we
shifted bullish eventually we shifted
bearish okay what caused this break is
this guy major har major High major low
pull back a bill above 50 what does it
make sense to be traded right now shorts
why because we're bearish so what we
have to be looking for right now is for
the 50 minute to go short okay but there
is a big but I have a rule in my
community so I'm gonna share something
with you that is uh I usually keep it
secret
as long as the 50 minute goes you go
with the 50 minute until you're wrong
why because in this case I've seen it
oftentimes the market decides to
actually shift the trend maybe there is
a daily demand zone right there and the
market is gonna turn bullish on The
Daily so what the 50 minute does bullish
bullish bullish bullish bullish bullish
bullish boys and it breaks the high okay
you're like I will follow he was Birch
why did we turn bullish well because of
daily and that is why I told you the
lower time frames always gonna Trump so
look at this great example
the market made this lower low it went
on and made a trend change
what caused the train change it's this
can you take a long cure absolutely you
can smash it another break of structure
what caused this breaker structure this
can you take along from here absolutely
but your stop was a bit big another
break of structure what caused this
breaker structure it's this can you take
a look here uh yes but it's Asia so you
don't take it because you can get swept
okay and then of course this was the
high this was the low all of this is
internal if you just care for the look
at the candles right that's the highest
point that's the lowest point although
it's internal you make a lot of mistakes
saying ah train change oh structure
break no that's internal the market TAPS
in goes on and breaks another structure
break so what you really see right now
is that the 50 minute is just
beautifully bullish so to me as long as
the 15 minute is bullish I go long
this is exactly where we broke the 15
minute High what caused the break it's
this little Zone retested broke up again
what caused this break it's the zone
right so heart hello demand we're
retesting that zone you can take a set
and forget approach play stop loss below
or you can go to the one minute let's
see how it looks like
there it is okay so that's the 50 minute
break the market pulls back so let's
first see okay so we tap into the Zone
do we take liquidity
yeah what's this
so do you remember from the liquidity
list what is this
it's structural liquidity it's it's fake
supply and demand because again people
are going to be looking to take a loan
from here and you can see that the
reaction there were people longing from
here guess where their stop loss was
right there and look at how the market
massively takes everything what about
this this is also supply and demand Zone
and this is why I told you guys do not
refine
don't look too much on the lower tires
and try to pick that sniper Ranger
because it's not about getting a sniper
entry it's about entering at the right
place
guess what there were buyers entering
from there look at the reaction they got
in they got it even here where was their
stop loss below the slope
look where the market goes and then what
it does later is it just aligns bullish
and that is when we strike after the
liquidity grab there's our Trend change
stop loss is 3.4 Pips for me if it's
below five Pips I smash the trade okay
and the result
TP in three minutes
why did it go so fast is because it
stopped out these Traders and it also
stopped out these Traders And when
everybody stop stopped out that is when
it goes and this is why I believe you
have to be looking for always for
liquidity gaps so hopefully this makes
sense it's very very very simple what I
want to show you right now it's
something amazing that I'm going to be
sharing with you this is a road map
right this is a flow chart
so let me try to break this down okay I
actually advise to to do this on your
own so this is just an example okay this
is what I use I have tweaked a little
bit towards what I teach you for my
community members it's it's way
different than that but let me give you
like a little breakdown so this is where
the major time frame is you see this is
where we start
okay if the following time frame is
bullish you go on the left if the fire
time frame is bearish you go on the
right let's say it's bullish okay so
what is it doing what is the current
phase of the market is it pushing
towards a weak High which looks like
this
right it's pushing towards a week high
or is it pulling back into 50 which
looks like this
we're still in the pullback okay so
depending on this then you flow okay so
then cool it's this phase so I dropped
to the 50 minute what do I do on the 50
minutes well if it's pushing towards the
weak High you want to go long so you
find the last clear 50 minute Zone that
calls the structure break okay and of
course you gotta wait for liquidity
that's it simple so that this one is
very simple all you need to do in this
case is just go long and do that for all
the time frame is taken what about this
guy so say that the market is pulling
back right here so then you have two
things that could happen is the market
still kind of pulling back into 50
percent
but it's still uh I mean above premium
so I see it's it's above it's bigger
than 50 is this right well well yeah
it's technically in premium in order for
us to buy this is premium this is
Discount we need the market to get into
discount so if it's above 50 then you
find what caused the 50 minute TC and
you trade this
as long as you are not in 50 so say here
we got the TC and even structure breaks
you can take those shorts until the 50
percent
that is this this case if the 50 minutes
I mean if the forward time frame has run
out tap the fifty percent right so it's
if it's at the 50 on the forage then you
wait for a 15 minute TC at hard time
from demand so again on the 40 time
frame you can have Demand right there
the market is usually tap into this
demand and the 50 minute is gonna align
so when the 50 minute aligns when it's
below the 50 you go to this profile
right there
okay because right now we're aligned so
we want to go again towards the weak
High
so hopefully it makes sense study this
chart I'm gonna go in examples right now
but I'm gonna share this with you you
can play with it you can do your own
okay and again Zone requirements in
order to have a Zone it must break
structure strongly with momentum leave
some imbalance it needs to be an
engulfing candle okay so there needs to
be a big engulfing candle if there is
not on the 15 minute to go to the 25
minute to the 30 minute and of course
you would like to see some sort of
manipulation taking liquidity like a
range took liquidity and then initiated
those are the most powerful supply and
demand zones and there are your entry
rules
identify the profile where are you in
terms of your macro Trend and where are
you in terms of your minor Trend right
there the 50 minute where is your supply
and demand Zone retest so again on the
50 minute where is your Zone okay and
then of course you can do the saf entry
the set and forget enter from The Zone
with a safe stop loss or you can go to
the Precision entry so you wait for a
liquidity grab you wait for a trend
change and then you execute and manage
the trade there is your cheat sheet
again Link in the description I'm gonna
send this to you right
so with that being said there are
additional entry models right this is
not all this is very simple and I want
you to go in your chart and try to
figure it out I have worked really hard
uh for my personal training to find out
like the best way to enter trades the
best way to also further capitalize on
trades uh if you get an initial entry
then we have like two three types of
entries aggressive one which is our
swing trading strategy we have the TC
entry and then we have the the
continuation entry so we have three
entry models that allow us to
continuously kind of get into trade and
scale into trade while keeping it
extremely systematic so again if you
want to learn absolutely everything The
Fanatic way of course is though is the
way to go right so right now I want to
jump on a chart let's jump on a chart
practice also with the with the tool
that I'm gonna give you and have a look
at how you can actually practice getting
into trades all right welcome to the
charts as you can see we have our flow
chart right there so I'm just gonna give
you an example I'm gonna try to keep it
two examples only so we can keep the
video short while I will try to explain
to you what I mean okay let me just
share with you an example we are
actually in a trade right now okay so
first of all let's of course do our
top-down analysis uh if you're no here
we shifted bearish right so the range so
yeah we can have definitely uh this
short right there and then we can have
other short right now the market then
broke structure down right so the market
was bearish but then uh it was uh
yesterday we came on and we actually
shifted the structure up and right now
we have
a brand new structure here well
forex.com uh yeah yeah definitely this
is also brake structure up happening
right there so currently this is our
higher low formation so let me first
talk about the trade we are right now
and then we're gonna jump onto two more
examples okay I'm gonna start talking a
lot right now so probably this video is
gonna go three hours a joke so what do
we have we have a push okay so we have a
push face fight because just zoom in
while keeping this thing right there so
we have a push phase right the market
made a new car hide this is our higher
low that caused the break of the heart
height
the market made a high ride there so
what do we want to see right now is for
the market to start pulling back below
50 okay so again what are we probably
bullish where are we pull back into 50
so now we drop to the 50 minute
okay let's bring this back up right
there man this one why can't it stay
just in one place can I lock it or
somehow uh
yeah okay doesn't matter I'm gonna keep
dragging it with me so again you can see
the market kind of made a new higher
high okay and the little example here is
that it kind of came in and tapped the
50 and then the short occurred a little
bit later okay so again attention to
details you could have definitely
skipped this short okay but let's just
stick to that okay the market is right
now bullish it's at a high
how do you know that our high is formed
when you have a trend change this is
exactly when the train changes occurs so
right now we are at this right now okay
the market is in premium we want to get
the market into discount in order to get
along so what we want to do is we trade
into the 50 which is counter Trend okay
so now 50 minute what caused the trend
change
it's this
right in this case we took uh we took a
slightly bigger Zone like that I think
it's on another time frame the market
pushed pulls back into the zone two
things you can do set and forget take
your trade from there stop loss above of
course a little bit bigger and you write
it down towards like the 50 which can
give you around 2R because that is one
of the trades you can take what we did
is we dropped to the one minute and we
did the Precision inch the market comes
in grabs liquidity on the left right and
what it does so what we have to wait for
right now is for the one minute to align
the one minute made a higher high the
one minute made the lower low train
change down the market came in gave us
an entry stop loss above four Pips and
uh it's a very choppy because we have a
CPI uh there right now but it it got us
to 3r
right so there is a trait very very very
very simple
that's it and this is again a counter
Trend rate so you can decide to risk if
you wish a little bit less but you can
see in just two minutes we frame the
trade follow the time frame higher high
15 minute time frame train change down
so we have actually the confidence we
don't try to keep longing as the market
is making the highs uh sorry to keep
shorting catching the top we wait for
the market to show us when the top is
formed and that is when we get into the
trade so let's see if this one is
actually going to go on and take out the
low I don't think so because we have
cpis we're probably gonna do this and
then it's gonna do some mad stuff
so there is one trade
let me show you another trade
can I just
okay nice I'm Gonna Keep copy pasting it
so let me show you right here exactly
right there if you ask the question the
following was bullet a bearish why did
it turn bullish let's check out the
daily what is the daily doing how to
break a structure up here what do we
have right there demand so what is the
daily doing it's bullish
so right we were bearish right there the
market made a massive push to the
downside they eventually ended up taking
it out why check your hard time frame
okay at this precise point right here
what we could have done okay well the
quality time frame right now is bearish
we drop our range okay so what are we
right now let me just put this back up
okay
so the file is bearish we're going to
the right we're put and we are right now
pulling back towards the 50 okay so we
are still below discount so we want to
get the market into premium so that we
can start shorting the market so what we
can do is we can counter trade trading
into the fifty percent so that is
currently our situation
when do we know that a lower low is
formed
again when we have a trend change so
again according to your rules according
to me the train change the current
exactly right there what caused the
train change in the zone can you take a
trade here absolutely yes do you do the
set and forget approach
like this and then Target like the 50
which in this case gave you a 3r and if
you decide to re to leave a runner oh
you're looking pretty good right you're
looking pretty good right or we can jump
to the one minutes let's see if we
actually got something on the one minute
hmm
hell yes with it
right the market comes in plot lows took
them out lower high blood lows took them
out this is exactly where we shifted
bullish on the on the one minute what
caused the shift bullish right here
there's your trade Precision entry stop
loss below I mean this stop loss is
ridiculous right two Pips and yeah then
you can Target like you can see the 15
minute High gives you 4r and if you go
towards the 50 it gives you 17 r
but this trade for me six o'clock I
don't trade at six man yeah well again
it's according to your style if you
trade New York station there is your
trade it literally caught the bottom
after a 50 minute train change set and
forget approach Precision entry
everything was there with liquidity wrap
as well
okay
another example early this week
uh so if I just
do
this just before it happened okay so
again this is hindsight guys okay I'm
just remember those examples I want to
show you examples okay I take losses my
win rate is 40 to 45 percent so again
what I show you Works 45 of the times so
again don't think that it's 100 please
I'm not one of those guys to pretend
like oh this is what you have to do
there is our high there is our lobe okay
so again back into structure high low
should be red but again where is our 50
boom so where is the market so you open
your chart seven o'clock okay you open
your your two where is the market what
is it doing bearish cool there we are
are we what are we doing right now well
we are currently at 50 above 50 so what
we have to be looking for is for the 15
minute uh for a 50 minute TC to align
bearish so then we can jump into
this phase
okay so let's see what we do we drop to
the 50 minute time frame
in this precise case
you have to be mastered Market structure
okay this is exactly where we broke the
50 minute low what caused the break of
the 50 minute low again you can you can
take it in numerous ways you can do this
for me it was actually this little guy
right there
so the market broke and this to me again
I was looking at this I didn't take this
trade by the way guys because it was
Monday bank holiday so I did not trade
but there was a perfect example of a
setup okay
so in this case we also have liquidity I
mean this is liquidity High an old high
this is liquidity high right so where
what does the market do Bank comes in
and smashes it why because there are
people trying to Short from here which
is internal structure remember so major
Folly High major value low on the 50
minute you also have to do the same
major 15 minute High major 50 minute low
everything inside you don't trade the
only thing you care about is how do I
get a short could we have gotten short
right there absolutely here absolutely
if you get your entry set up okay but on
the next day we come in right there the
Asian high is taken liquidity is taken
we drop to the one minute
so the laminate takes lots of liquidity
right now so what we have to wait for is
for the one minute to align okay
technically the one minute the lines
right here you can also take this that's
what happens
boom the one minute aligned it broke all
structure so it's exactly this time
where the one minute has aligned after a
liquidity wrap so you just take your
trade right nowadays I don't even draw
zones in one minute because all I need
to see is that I have a safe stop loss
like in this case I can be entering like
even from here with a five Pips or if I
wish a little bit tighter I can then
turn from here let's just say like I
don't know four Pips or something
conservative what can you target well
first of all you can Target a 50 minute
low where in this case it's this or you
can just Target again guys targets are
up to you I always advise three r four
five hour if you can get this you're
absolutely golden don't swing to
defenses okay so let's do like a regular
like in this case we're trading with the
trend so we can do 4r and yeah again it
was bank holiday
the market reacted it came uh I think it
came one more time
yeah it came one more time right but you
can see the Strong high
remains intact okay and yeah eventually
if I just jump uh to another time frame
eventually we massively dropped so it
turned into actually this one turned
into a massive trade lower
okay so hopefully you get the you get
the the mindset you get actually how it
works right it just works every single
time again if I even if I again right
here you can see here we had uh there
was a slight
here we have this massive push lower
that let's say caused the breakup
structure down so what are we doing we
draw the range okay say we're say we're
right there the market is just making a
new lower low we usually like wait for
the first bullish candle but again we're
on the 50 minute because the 50 minutes
is going to give us a trend change so
they jump on the 50 minute okay uh the
15 minute online that I remember this
day you have to line right here broke
down broke up so can you take a set and
forget approach here absolutely to me it
was a little bit too early and then you
can see the market starts rolling you
usually want to trade it towards the 50
okay Boom the market is above 50 so here
you have guys two choices
if we are at fifty percent so in this
case we're bearish
uh pull back into 50 we're at 50 so you
either have to wait for a 50 minute TC
to align down so you can go pro Trend
with the bearish one or as I told you
you follow 15 minutes until you're wrong
okay 50 minute broke here boom 50 minute
broke here boom right this one did not
get retested uh let's see if this one is
going to get retested
nope but again what we did is we broke
another one what caused this break it's
this okay so there is your setup you
keep following the trend
set and forget approach boom stop loss
below six flip stop loss again targeting
3r because for swing trades you don't
want to Target way too much same thing
you can drop on the one minute okay what
do we have here let me just
get this out of the way for a little bit
what do we have here well again we have
that same thing right we have lots of
zones right there that are potentially
gonna get taken let's see if they get
taken actually boom okay so again people
look to enter from there they enter from
here stop loss is below they get taken
so what are we looking for right now is
for the one minute to align
there's your alignment what's the stop
loss three Pips let's just smash the
trade go for 3r like in this case uh for
a tight stop loss I usually do 4r
and we get another stop loss right so
that's cool okay amazing example very
good let's see let's see what happens so
we got a stop loss right the market
broke down then we look for the market
to break up oh yeah oh guys I remember
this trade so so this is the trade I
took two stop losses last week on Monday
why because I was I didn't play the set
and forget approach I played the one
minute approach so uh this is where so
let me see
oh yeah so this is where we aligned and
yeah then the second trade was right
here so then I think here I made a
mistake as well that I place a tight
stop loss that I don't remember but
again we align here again so even if you
take a stop loss you keep waiting
because as long as your zone is intact
if you get another Trend change you can
still enter into the trade right and uh
yeah I think eventually we tapped so I
think yeah pretty much the second trade
that took us from here but I took two
stop loss on this one so maybe I took
even a stop loss here I don't really
remember what I did but again you just
wait for it you wait for the train
change oh no no no I took a break even
I took a break even here because I was a
scared bastard yeah but then again as
you can see we run into the highs and
the swing trade is looking way better
okay
so pretty much those are the chat
examples make sure to actually go on and
utilize this chart I'm going to share
this with you uh via email I'm gonna
send it to you so make sure to click in
the description so right now let's go
and wrap it up all right we've come all
the way until the end so this is the end
of the poor video series which actually
turned five so after this do you feel a
better Trader type in the comments below
if you do feel like a better Trader what
were your main insights from all the
videos what did you learn and are you
already having success by now you should
have built your risk management plan
first video understood basic and
advanced Market structure second video
supply and demand Concepts and how to
use them third liquidity fourth and
right now Master two very simple entry
systems on this video so again this is a
great Foundation I mean I really went
ahead and given you a lot of tools a lot
of stuff a lot of Concepts that really
work amazing okay so what right now what
I advise you to do go back to video one
and cover them again because again just
by watching a single video once it's not
gonna make you understand the concepts
if you don't see them every single day
so this is why in the community we're
here showing up every single day and
pretty much if you follow us for like
for one month inside the community uh
you pretty much become masters of the
concepts okay so focus on the technical
videos especially you don't need to
watch the training plan videos three
times right so focus on the technical
videos which are like all the videos
after the training plan take notes study
find examples back test see how it works
figure out how it works for you figure
out your time frames figure out
everything okay and then of course try
to build the strategy section of your
trading plan because again first with it
risk and money management we did
monetary goals we did your why we did
everything but then the second part of
your plan is to have a strategy in place
again hard time frames minor time frames
Angel time frames Angel strategy trade
management everything right so
that's it we're wrapping it up so again
what would you like to see further we
wrapped up the series hopefully found
lots of value with well throughout this
series we actually hit 100 000
subscribers which is absolutely insane
right I want to keep providing so what
would you like to see do you have any
content ideas just let me know okay I
love you all thank you for all the
support I give all of this knowledge uh
to actually help you get a better Trader
learn what actually works in the market
and avoid all the BS that is out there
so without said
thank you so much once again and I'll
talk to you on my next videos hopefully
you're gonna crush the markets with all
these Concepts and if you have any
questions you always know where to find
me the best place is via email at
support trainingfanatic.com of course
leave a comment I'm always there to
answer and uh yeah talk to you soon